In 1968, democracy refused to back down.
The Trial of the Chicago 7 is a drama, history film directed by Aaron Sorkin.
What was supposed to be a peaceful protest turned
into a violent clash with the police.
What followed was one of the most notorious trials in history.
Tom Hayden, played by Eddie Redmayne.
Abbie Hoffman, played by Sacha Baron Cohen.
William Kunstler, played by Mark Rylance.
Richard Schultz, played by Joseph Gordon-Levitt.
Judge Julius Hoffman, played by Frank Langella.
Jerry Rubin, played by Jeremy Strong.
The Trial of the Chicago 7 is a 2020 American historical legal
drama film written and directed by Aaron Sorkin.
The film follows the Chicago Seven, a group of anti–Vietnam War protesters charged with conspiracy and crossing
state lines with the intention of inciting riots at the 1968 Democratic National Convention in Chicago.
It features an ensemble cast including Yahya Abdul-Mateen II, Sacha Baron Cohen, Daniel Flaherty, Joseph Gordon-Levitt, Michael Keaton,
Frank Langella, John Carroll Lynch, Eddie Redmayne, Noah Robbins, Mark Rylance, Alex Sharp, Ben Shenkman, and Jeremy Strong.
Sorkin wrote the screenplay in 2007, with the intent of Steven
Spielberg directing the film and cast mostly unknown actors.
After the 2007 Writers Guild of America strike and budget concerns forced Spielberg to drop out as director, Sorkin was announced as
director in October 2018, and much of the cast joined the same month, with Spielberg instead serving as executive producer.
Filming took place in the fall of 2019 in Chicago and around New Jersey.
Originally planned for a theatrical release by Paramount Pictures, the distribution
rights to the film were sold to Netflix due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
The Trial of the Chicago 7 was released in selected theaters on September 25,
2020, and began streaming digitally on Netflix on October 16.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who praised the performances (particularly from Baron Cohen),
Sorkin's screenplay, the cinematography, the editing and the modern parallels to the 1960s.
The film earned six nominations at the 93rd Academy Awards, including
Best Picture and Best Supporting Actor for Baron Cohen.
It also received five nominations at the 78th Golden Globe Awards (winning for Best Screenplay), three at the 27th Screen Actors Guild
Awards (winning Outstanding Performance by a Cast in a Motion Picture), and three at the 74th British Academy Film Awards.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, right and justice,
political activism, black panther party, based on true story.
The tone is dark and emotional.